{"id":"2018_18","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"Look to the Lord and his strength; seek his face always.\" â€“ 1 Chronicles 16:11","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_18_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_2","questionText":"2. From the past week's study, what made the most significant impact to you in the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 2 Samuel 7:1-7; 1 Chronicles 17:1-6; 22:8; 28:3.\nGod rejected David's request to build God a house.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:1-7"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"17:1-6"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"22:8"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"28:3"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_18_3","questionText":"3. What did David want to do for the Lord? Why? Was God pleased with David's request? (2 Chronicles 6:8)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"2 Chronicles","verse":"6:8"}]},{"id":"2018_18_4","questionText":"4. What reasons did God give David for not proceeding? What do you learn about God from these reasons?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_5","questionText":"5. When have you had God say \"no\" to something you wanted? What lessons did you learn?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 2 Samuel 7:8-17; 1 Chronicles 17:7-15; Psalm 89:35-37.\nGod promised to build David a dynasty.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:8-17"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"17:7-15"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"89:35-37"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_18_6","questionText":"6. What were the main promises of God's covenant with David? To what New Testament person does it ultimately refer? (For help, see Isaiah 9:6-7; Matthew 1:1-16 or any other Scripture reference.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Isaiah","verse":"9:6-7"},{"book":"Matthew","verse":"1:1-16"}]},{"id":"2018_18_7","questionText":"7. What warnings and encouragements stand out to you from these promises?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_8","questionText":"8. Looking back, how has God revealed His wisdom and love through His plans for your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 7:18-24; 1 Chronicles 17:16-22.\nDavid marveled at God's matchless greatness.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:18-24"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"17:16-22"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_18_9","questionText":"9. Describe David's response to God.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_10","questionText":"10. Which of David's thoughts and beliefs about God are most meaningful to you? Why?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_11","questionText":"11. What did David recognize God doing for himself, his family and Israel? How have you seen and responded to unexpected blessings in your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 2 Samuel 7:25-29; 1 Chronicles 17:23-27; Psalm 89:19-37.\nDavid prayed for God's continued blessing.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:25-29"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"17:23-27"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"89:19-37"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_18_12","questionText":"12. Define \"covenant\" using a dictionary. Was God's covenant with David conditional or unconditional? Explain.","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_13","questionText":"13. What reasons did David give for his courage and confidence to pray? How does God encourage you to pray?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_18_14","questionText":"14. Though not written by David, Psalm 89 is often read along with God's covenant in 2 Samuel 7. From the Psalm, how are God's covenant and God's love linked together?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"89:1-999"},{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:1-999"}]},{"id":"2018_18_15","questionText":"15. From the psalm, how does God describe Himself? How would remembering these attributes help you in your current situation?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 2 Samuel 7; 1 Chronicles 17; Psalm 89:19-37.","readVerse":[{"book":"2 Samuel","verse":"7:1-999"},{"book":"1 Chronicles","verse":"17:1-999"},{"book":"Psalm","verse":"89:19-37"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_18_16","questionText":"16. What did you learn about God, and what did you learn about yourself?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}